All the world will be your enemy, Prince with a Thousand Enemies, and when they
catch you, they will kill you... but first they must catch you.
Watership Down is a adventure, animation, drama film directed by Martin Rosen.
When the warren belonging to a community of rabbits is threatened, a brave group led by Fiver,
Bigwig, Blackberry and Hazel leave their homeland in a search of a safe new haven.
Hazel (voice), played by John Hurt.
Fiver (voice), played by Richard Briers.
Bigwig (voice), played by Michael Graham Cox.
Captain Holly (voice), played by John Bennett.
Chief Rabbit (voice), played by Ralph Richardson.
Blackberry (voice), played by Simon Cadell.
Watership Down is a 1978 British animated adventure-drama film, written, produced, and
directed by Martin Rosen and based on the 1972 novel by Richard Adams.
It features the voices of John Hurt, Richard Briers, Harry Andrews, Simon Cadell,
Nigel Hawthorne, Roy Kinnear, and Zero Mostel in his final film role.
This feature length animation was financed by a consortium of British financial institutions
and distributed by Cinema International Corporation in the United Kingdom.
It was released on 19 October 1978 and was an immediate success, becoming
the sixth-most popular film of 1979 at the UK box office.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
gore, trap, anthropomorphism, seagull.
The tone is emotional.